Yassine Haimouch — Frontend Developer

github.com/yassinehaimouch yassinehaimouch@proton.me linkedin/in/yassinehaimouch +212-6412-06132

PROFILE

I'm a software engineer mainly focused on React ecosystem. I have multiple years of experience in both UI/UX and Frontend Development. Over the past 3 years, I've strengthened fundamentals in web engineering that I'm eager to deploy on challenging projects to expand my current skill set and tech stack.

SKILLS

- HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | TypeScript | Node JS | React JS | Next JS | C | C++
- Tailwind CSS | Bootstrap | Styled Components | SASS | Redux Toolkit | React Query | Storybook | Jest | Tesing Library
- Git | GitHub | Bitbucket | Npm | Yarn | Azure | Jasmine | Karma | Testing/TDD | Vim | Linux | Vercel | Netlify
- Figma | Adobe Photoshop | Adobe Illustrator | Adobe XD

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer, Blocxs BV - Amsterdam, Netherlands

July 2023 - Present

- Frontend developer, writing automated test scripts using industry-standard testing frameworks (Jasmine, Karma) to streamline the testing process and enhance testing efficiency.
- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams, including developers and product manager, to understand project requirements and design test cases accordingly.

Software Engineer & Content Creator, Instagram - instagram.com/gitcoder/

April 2022 - Present

Software Engineering, Tech Life, Coding, Resources, Blogging.

Frontend Engineer, Upwork

May 2019 - Present

- Building responsive and user-friendly websites and web applications using (Figma, React JS, and Tailwind)
- Experienced in git workflow, Testing/TDD, and Performance Optimization for high-quality code.
- Demonstrated ability to maintain open communication with clients, ensuring satisfaction and timely delivery.
- Strong focus on writing clean, maintainable, and reusable code for efficient collaboration and codebase management.

Software Engineer, 1337 School - 42 Network

June 2021 - July 2021

- Successfully completed intensive coding projects and exercises, showcasing strong problem-solving and time management skills.
- Collaborated effectively with diverse peers on complex programming challenges, enhancing teamwork and communication abilities.
- Demonstrated adaptability and resilience in a demanding and competitive environment.

EDUCATION

Epic React Dev, Course by Kent C. Dodds

High School Diploma, Physics

2017 - 2018

Moroccan — Diploma

PROJECTS

Portfolio: Designed and developed my portfolio using Figma, React JS, Tailwind CSS, Framer Motion.

Bookshelf: Built a full React application from scratch using (React JS, React Query, Bootstrap).

Advanced React Patterns: Built simple and flexible React Components and Hooks using modern patterns.

<u>Rick & Morty</u>: Developed a project that consumes The Rick and Morty API to create a visually appealing interface showcasing all characters from the show.